CV David Skødt Lauritsen

Country: Denmark (willing to relocate)
City: Juelsminde (willing to relocate)

Age: 27

Phone: +45 51 51 18 97

Mail: <u>david@davidskodt.com</u>

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/in/DavidSkodt.com</u>
Website: <u>davidskodt.com</u> (work in progress)



Driven UX designer

I'm David, nice to meet you! I recently acquired a passion for User Experience (UX) design. In March, 2017, I decided to work towards becoming a full-blown UX designer through self-study. My education (M. Sc. In Medialogy with a Specialization in Interaction) had introduced me to the role of the UXer already, but it took some time away from my studies to realize that design was my calling. I set out to make myself familiar with terminology and practices, and I started strategizing when I was in the middle of my stay at Aalborg Sportshøjskole. Through books, articles, video courses and through doing, I improved my skills and began to engage in small projects to hone my design skills. I am still at it, learning new things every day. I also trained myself in HTML & CSS in order to put together a portfolio website for my projects. I recently attended the Design Matters 17 conference in Copenhagen (October 2017) to learn as much as possible, do a bit of networking and participate in the discussions on conversational UI.

Aside from my personal projects, I enjoy working in teams the most. I consider myself a team player who enjoys both the social dynamics of working as part of a team. Furthermore, I think that working closely with others is a great opportunity to get intimate insight into the many aspects of the development process. The most recent examples of me working in teams have been through my volunteer work with Red Barnet Ungdom, where I was volunteer of the month (September, 2017), and through my research during my university years. My time at Aalborg University lead to three publications of which I am very proud.

Core Competencies

UX Research

- Capable in setting up- and running usability tests with real users.
- Practical experience from personal project and courses at Aalborg University

Prototyping, wireframing & mockups

- Most of my designs start on paper before becoming digital.
- Why spend time guessing later in the process, when the important choices can be validated before writing any code?

Presentation and storytelling

- I practice good storytelling and I strive to present information clearly.
- I have experience in speaking at international conferences.

Motivated self-development

- I am always eager to learn new things and improve on my existing skills.
- I read books and articles, listen to podcasts and take online video courses. I am active in design debates on twitter, slack and forums.

Education	
10.2016 – 06.2017	Student at Aalborg Sportshøjskole
	 There was a lot of weight put on team building and solving practical problems. During my stay, I also used my spare time to improve my UX related skills and create my online portfolio website.
08.2013 – 06.2015	Master of Science in Medialogy with a Specialization in Interaction
	 Multidisciplinary education with courses ranging from programming and statistics to user experience design and research
	My primary roles were test facilitator, researcher and project manager
	 The title of my Master's thesis was: "Aurally Aided Visual Search Performance Comparing Virtual Audio Systems". It was published through AES, and presented at the 137th AES Conference in Los Angeles, USA.
08.2010 – 06.2013	Bachelor of Science in Medialogy, Aalborg Universitet
	 Multidisciplinary education with courses ranging from programming and statistics to user experience design and research
	 The most important skills I picked up during this time was a good understanding of research, statistics and working in teams.
	 We published "Differences in human audio localization performance between a HRTF- and a non-HRTF audio system" through ACM, and presented it at the 8th Audio Mostly Conference in Pitå, Sweden).
Work Experience	
04.2016 – 09.2016	Teacher at Glud primary school
	 I was, in almost every aspect, the stable teacher for a class of 5th graders. I took care of their curriculum, teacher-parent relations and I taught most of their classes. Their original teacher was on long-term sick leave.
	 I taught Danish, English, history, religion, physical exercise and arts and crafts.
	 I received great praise from teachers, students, parents and the principal for my work. I have a written recommendation from the principal.
08.2014 – 12.2014	Frontend developer at VOLUME (internship)
	• This internship replaced the 9. semester in my M. Sc. at Aalborg University.
	 The work focused on interaction, user-friendliness, gamification and scaling on a web-based platform.

• I often assisted coworkers and my boss with general computer issues.

Volunteer Work

09.2016 - 06.2017

Voulenteer at Red Barnet Ungdom (Independent Save the Children youth project)

- As a volunteer, we went to an asylum center on a bimonthly to engage the children there with play, activities and cultural events.
- I have been a very active volunteer, attended meetings and visits alike as well as directed and edited a music video intended for fun and promotion (the video can be viewed on portfolio website).
- I had the honor of being "volunteer of the month" for the month of September, 2017.

08.2013 - 06.2015

Matcher at AAU Matchmaking

- Volunteer work with focus on establishing contact and cooperation between students at Aalborg University and local companies.
- Focus on communication and networking.

Software Experience

Programming languages: HTML, CSS (and Bootstrap), Javascript, C#/C++, ActionScript 3.0.

Software: Photoshop, Mockplus, Unity3D, Maya, 3DS Max, Sony Vegas, LaTeX, R.

Microsoft office: Very experienced with all office products.

Lingual Skills

Danish: Fluent (5/5), English: Fluent (5/5), German: Good (3/5), Spanish: Fair (2/5)

Hobbies and interests

In the summer of 2015, I headed out on an epic journey: the Appalachian Trail. For about ~2.900 kilometers over a period of 6 months, I hiked a trail that crosses 14 state lines on the east coast of the US. While arduous, the trip was a great experience and it provided plenty of learning experiences. I had to plan the entire ordeal, which was a great logistical task, but most of the things I learned were inward. It has made me a very confident individual who dares to try, in all things. In general, I am a very optimistic individual who loves people, the outdoors, good food (both the cooking and eating aspects) and rock climbing.